https://www.doigandsmith.co.uk/privacy-policy/?#privacy-cookie-policy

Doig+Smith > Privacy Policy
BACKGROUND:
Doig and Smith Ltd understand that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits this website, www.doigandsmith.co.uk (“Our Site”) and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a manner that is consistent with Our obligations and your rights under the law.
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of Our Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of Our Site. If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Our Site immediately.
1. Definitions and Interpretation
In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:
"Account"
means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site;
"Cookie"
means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our Site. Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in section 13, below;
"Cookie Law"
means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003;
"Personal Data"
means any and all data that relates to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from that data. In this case, it means personal data that you give to Us via Our Site. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"); and
"We/Us/Our"
means Doig and Smith Ltd, a limited company registered in Scotland under company number SC372452, whose registered address and whose main trading address is Kintyre House, 205 West George Street, Glasgow.
2.Information About Us
2.1Our Site, doigandsmith.co.uk, is owned and operated by Doig and Smith Ltd, a limited company registered in Scotland under company number SC372452, whose registered address and whose main trading address is Kintyre House, 205 West George Street, Glasgow.
2.2Our Business Manager is the first point of contact in the event of any questions regarding data and can be contacted by email at enquiries@doigandsmith.co.uk, by telephone on 0141 241 4600, or by post at Kintyre House, 205 West George Street, Glasgow.
3.What Does This Policy Cover?
This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that We have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and We advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.
4.Your Rights
4.1As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR, which this Policy and Our use of personal data have been designed to uphold:
4.1.1The right to be informed about Our collection and use of personal data;
4.1.2The right of access to the personal data We hold about you (see section 12);
4.1.3The right to rectification if any personal data We hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete (please contact Us using the details in section 14);
4.1.4The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask Us to delete any personal data We hold about you (We only hold your personal data for a limited time, as explained in section 6 but if you would like Us to delete it sooner, please contact Us using the details in section 14);
4.1.5The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
4.1.6The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);
4.1.7The right to object to Us using your personal data for particular purposes; and
4.1.8Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.
4.2If you have any cause for complaint about Our use of your personal data, please contact Us using the details provided in section 14 and We will do Our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK’s supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner’s Office.
4.3For further information about your rights, please contact the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.
5.What Data Do We Collect?
Depending upon your use of Our Site, We may collect some or all of the following personal and non-personal data (please also see section 13 on Our use of Cookies and similar technologies):
5.1name;
5.2business/company name;
5.3contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers;
5.4demographic information such as post code, preferences and interests;
5.5IP address;
5.6web browser type and version;
5.7operating system;
5.8a list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on Our Site, and the site you exit to;
6.How Do We Use Your Data?
6.1All personal data is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with Our obligations and safeguard your rights under the GDPR at all times. For more details on security see section 7, below.
6.2Our use of your personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for Our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to Our use of your personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails), or because it is in Our legitimate interests. Specifically, We may use your data for the following purposes:
6.2.1Providing and managing your access to Our Site;
6.2.2Replying to emails from you;
6.2.3Supplying you with emails that you have opted into (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time by contacting our our Business Manager mentioned in section 2.2;
6.2.4Market research;
6.2.5Analysing your use of Our Site and gathering feedback to enable Us to continually improve Our Site and your user experience;
6.3You have the right to withdraw your consent to Us using your personal data at any time, and to request that We delete it.
6.4We do not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Data will therefore be retained for the following periods (or its retention will be determined on the following bases):
6.4.1Ongoing authorised communications between Doig and Smith and yourself will require that we retain your basic communication information indefinitely until a time where communication ceases between you and Our Company; at this time your information shall only be retained for a maximum time of two years after which it will be deleted.
6.4.2Unless being used for direct, authorised communications between Doig and Smith and yourself, all other saved information will be retained for a maximum time of two years after which it will be deleted from our records.
7.How and Where Do We Store Your Data?
7.1We only keep your personal data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above in section 6, and/or for as long as We have your permission to keep it.
7.2Your data will only be stored in the UK.
7.3Data security is very important to Us, and to protect your data We have taken suitable measures to safeguard and secure data collected through Our Site.
8.Do We Share Your Data?
8.1Subject to section 8.2, We will not share any of your data with any third parties for any purposes.
8.2In certain circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal data, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with legal obligations, a court order, or a governmental authority.
9.What Happens If Our Business Changes Hands?
9.1We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business. Any personal data that you have provided will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business that is being transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use that data only for the same purposes for which it was originally collected by Us.
9.2In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you will not be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.
10.How Can You Control Your Data?
10.1In addition to your rights under the GDPR, set out in section 4, when you submit personal data via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. In particular, We aim to give you strong controls on Our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in Our emails and at the point of providing your details).
10.2You may also wish to sign up to one or more of the preference services operating in the UK: The Telephone Preference Service (“the TPS”), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (“the CTPS”), and the Mailing Preference Service (“the MPS”). These may help to prevent you receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.
11.Your Right to Withhold Information
11.1You may access Our Site without providing any data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Our Site you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.
11.2You may restrict Our use of Cookies. For more information, see section 13.
12.How Can You Access Your Data?
You have the right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Under the GDPR, no fee is payable and We will provide any and all information in response to your request free of charge. Please contact Us for more details at enquiries@doigandsmith.co.uk, or using the contact details below in section
13.Our Use of Cookies
13.1Our Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer or device. First party Cookies are those placed directly by Us and are used only by Us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve Our services. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure that your privacy and personal data is protected and respected at all times
13.2All Cookies used by and on Our Site are used in accordance with current Cookie Law.
13.3Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device, you will be shown a small pop-up window at the bottom of your screen requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling Us to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of Our Site may not function fully or as intended.
13.4Certain features of Our Site depend on Cookies to function. Cookie Law deems these Cookies to be “strictly necessary”. These Cookies are shown below in section 13.5. Your consent will not be sought to place these Cookies, but it is still important that you are aware of them. You may still block these Cookies by changing your internet browser’s settings as detailed below in section 13.9, but please be aware that Our Site may not work properly if you do so. We have taken great care to ensure that your privacy is not at risk by allowing them.
13.5The following first party Cookies may be placed on your computer or device:
Name of Cookie
PHPSESSID
Purpose
Each visitor to our website is automatically issued a unique Session ID. This ID is hidden and unintrusive to the user. It tracks user interaction within the website as well as the temporary shopping basket contents for guest accounts.
Strictly Necessary
Yes
Name of Cookie
catAccCookies
Purpose
A cookie that tracks if the visitor has acknowledged that this site uses cookies.
Strictly Necessary
No
13.6Our Site uses analytics services provided by Google Analytics. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse anonymous usage information, enabling Us to better understand how Our Site is used. This, in turn, enables Us to improve Our Site and the services offered through it. You do not have to allow Us to use these Cookies, however whilst Our use of them does not pose any risk to your privacy or your safe use of Our Site, it does enable Us to continually improve Our Site, making it a better and more useful experience for you.
13.7The analytics service(s) used by Our Site use(s) Cookies to gather the required information.
13.8The analytics service(s) used by Our Site use(s) the following Cookies:
Name of Cookie
__utma
First / Third Party
First
Provider
Google
Purpose
A persistent Google Analytics cookie which tracks user visits to our website. This cookie keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site pertaining to the cookie, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred.
Name of Cookie
__utmz
First / Third Party
First
Provider
Google
Purpose
A Google Analytics cookie which tracks where the visitor came from, what search engine they used, what link they clicked on, what keyword they used, and where in the world they accessed our website from.
Name of Cookie
_ga
First / Third Party
First
Provider
Google
Purpose
A Google Analytics cookie which assigns each visitor a unique ID and records the time at which they visited our website.
Name of Cookie
_gat
First / Third Party
First
Provider
Google
Purpose
A Google cookie that stops the potential abuse of any Pay-Per-Click advertising campaigns. This cookie does not store any user information.
13.9In addition to the controls that We provide, you can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. Most internet browsers also enable you to choose whether you wish to disable all cookies or only third party cookies. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser or the documentation that came with your device.
13.10You can choose to delete Cookies on your computer or device at any time, however you may lose any information that enables you to access Our Site more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, login and personalisation settings.
13.11It is recommended that you keep your internet browser and operating system up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser and manufacturer of your computer or device if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.
14.Contacting Us
If you have any questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us by email at enquiries@doigandsmith.co.uk, by telephone on 0141 241 4600, or by post at Kintyre House, 205 West George Street, Glasgow. Please ensure that your query is clear, particularly if it is a request for information about the data We hold about you (as under section 12, above).
15.Changes to Our Privacy Policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time (for example, if the law changes). Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
This Doig+Smith website uses cookies:
Find out more.Okay, thanks
